ZOYA BUYANKINA

SUMMARY:

A young, self-motivated and achievement-oriented Business Development Analyst with more than 3 years of experience in the business development process and different marketing fields. Proven experience in planning in coordinating marketing policies and programs, such as determining the demand for products and services offered by a firm and its competitors in order to identify new potential customers. Excellent problem-solving skills and ability to perform well in a team.

Phone: +1 (646) 644 5415

zbuyankina@hotmail.com

LinkedIn

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE:

Research Service Bureau, Insurance Investigations

Morristown, NJ January 2017 – April 2020

Business Development Analyst

- Performed research and analysis of the insurance investigations industry, developed new strategies to capture business opportunities (B2B).
- Involved in client acquisition/retention and building relationships with C- level executives
 of the Top-200 carriers and industry associations.
- Reviewed customer feedback and then suggested ways to improve in the business process, which increased the satisfaction rate.
- Prepared marketing, advertising strategies and plans. Objectives include; organizing promotional presentations and developing marketing materials.
- Collected and analyzing data, performing SWOT analyses, identifying trends and insights in order to achieve maximum ROI for future marketing campaigns.
- Directed all meetings and produced presentations for clients.

Fidelity Media, Online Advertising Agency

Kaliningrad, Russia January 2012 – August 2014

Account Manager

- Managed marketing campaigns with CPM and CPC pricing models for banners, pop-up
- Identified potential new clients and business opportunities.
- Designed marketing strategies and media proposals that support existing and recruit new clients.
- Negotiated pricing and acquired inventory.
- Customer retention by prompt response to requests and daily assistance to clients.
- Monitored ongoing advertising campaigns performance.
- Provided weekly and monthly reports, maintained proper records of all orders, invoices, etc.

Vester Retail Holding

Kaliningrad, Russia April 2010 - January 2012

Marketing Manager

- Developed and managed the promotion, annual marketing programs to establish and grow brand awareness in the market, increase profitability and customer retention.
- Managed the budget among marketing campaigns, media plans and promotional tools.
- Organized and maintained the departmental calendar, including store events, promotions, special events, anniversaries.
- Wrote creative briefs for merchandising and advertising including TV, print, radio, interactive and in-store POP to execute in-mall events and promotions in order to drive traffic to the stores.
- Managed Brand Ambassadors for promotional events, training and recapping results of events.
- Generated campaign's performance report based on ROI.

LANGU

EDUCATION:

Pace University, Lubin School of Business MBA in Investment Management Part-Time, GPA 3.5

New York, USA 2017 – Present

Kaliningrad State Technical University BA & MA degree in Business Administration GPA 3.68 (on a scale of 4.0)

Kaliningrad, Russia 2005-2010

SKILLS:

Market Research & Analysis

Business to Business Sales (B2B)

Account Management

Business Development

Brand Management

Strategic Partnerships

Online Marketing and Advertising

Public Relations & Promotions

Client Acquisition/Retention

TECHNOLOGY:

Adept at Microsoft Office: Word, Excel, Outlook and PowerPoint;

Intermediate Level – Adobe Photoshop

LANGUAGES:

English – fluent;

Russian – native speaker.